JONATHAN LEE

MATHEMATICS AND ECONOMICS

Seattle, Washington 98125

iondeanlee@gmail.com

(206) 466-9242

www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-lee-4b831025b

https://github.com/JONATHAN-

LEE-01/Portfolio

OBJECTIVE

Detailed-oriented and number driven student with 5 years of restaurant management experience who is seeking to capitalize on technical experience in Rstudio, Stata, Python, and Microsoft Suite. I am ready to combine my fast-paced work experience and organizational and communication skills with my interests in economics, finance, and public policy to analyze and develop effective strategies within a company and its community.

EDUCATION

B.A. Mathematics and Economics

Western Washington University | Bellingham, WA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student Ambassador

Western Washington University | Bellingham, WA

Nov 2022 - Aug 2023

- Hand-selected to represent the WWU Mathematics Department as a liaison between students and faculty, and the Dean of CSE.
- Designed and implemented the Mathematics Department's first Mentorship Program.
- Sought to engage in issues around advocacy, equity, and diversity in STEM.
- Held weekly office hours to engage with students on topics around advocacy, diversity, equity and experiences in STEM.
- · Analyzed survey data from mentors and mentees to improve future recruitment methods.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Server/Person in Charge (PIC)

Server/Person in Charge (PIC) | Bellingham, WA

Aug 2020 - Present

- Kept written records of sales numbers daily to ensure accurate revenue numbers.
- Memorized entire food menu and up to 12 different parties' orders under high-stress environments.
- Communicated appropriately and efficiently to back of house colleagues to execute customer requests accurately.
- Described menu items persuasively to increase sales.

Kitchen Management Consultant/Lead Line Cook

The Black Cat | Bellingham, WA

Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

- · Optimized food costs by implementing daily specials to incorporate residual ingredients.
- · Utilized proficency in Microsoft Excel to assist management in tracking food costs and labor.
- Streamlined the kitchen by reorganizing appliances and strategies to improve the flow of employees and outgoing dishes.
- Adapted to minimal work space through effective communication.

Lead Line Cook/PIC

Aslan Brewing Co. | Bellingham, WA

Jul 2017 - Nov 2019

- Worked efficiently with a positive attitude in a high-stress environment within a high-volume restaurant.
- Facilitated and directed up to twelve line/prep cooks to execute food menu items accurately in an consistent, organized, and timely manner.
- Tracked inventory daily to ensure FIFO and provide the company with its annual COGS and optimize menu pricing.

Painter's Assistant

MadeRadbyTony | Bellingham, WA

Sep 2017 - May 2019

- Meticulously prepared bicycles for custom paint.
- Sandblasted aluminum bicycle frames and hand-sanded carbon fiber bicycle frames.
- Most notably, assisted in custom painted bicycles for Jason Momoa and Jill Kintner.